{
    "question": "Pilihan alat transportasi saat ini sangat banyak. Alat transportasi yang paling tepat    dipilih ketika bepergian jauh lintas pulau adalah .... dibantu ya kak\u200b",
    "attachments": [],
    "answers": [
        {
            "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>Pesawat</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>semoga membantu ya kak...</p>",
            "attachments": []
        },
        {
            "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>kapal dan pesawat</p><p></p><p>semoga membantu</p>",
            "attachments": []
        }
    ],
    "related_questions": [
        {
            "slug": "jakarta-isthan-sidoarjo-179",
            "question": "Jakarta is....than sidoarjo",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>big</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>artinya lebih besar</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "it-is-a-vehicle-it-is-big-and-199",
            "question": "It is a vehicle. it is big and?..",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>its a car</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>maaf kalau salah</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "1-what-do-you-say-bahasa-pertama-in-english-2-when-do-you-e-749",
            "question": "1. What do you say \" bahasa pertama\" in English?    2. When do you express compliment ?\r\n3. What do you say \" prestasi\" in English ?\r\n4. What is the social purpose of congratulating people?",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>1. first language</p><p>2. when we want to express praise, appreciate, or admiration to someone</p><p>3. achievement</p><p>4. to respond to someone&#039;s achievement or success</p><p></p><p>Semoga terbantu, maap kalo salah. Kalo bener jan lupa dijadikan jawaban tercerdas yak\u270c</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>arti soal :</p><p></p><p>1. Apa yang Anda katakan \"bahasa pertama\" dalam bahasa Inggris?</p><p>2. Kapan Anda mengungkapkan pujian?</p><p>3. Apa kata \"prestasi\" dalam bahasa Inggris?</p><p>4. Apa tujuan sosial dari memberi selamat kepada orang lain?</p><p></p><p>jawab :</p><p></p><p>1.first language</p><p>2.when I see someone great</p><p>3.achievement</p><p>4.so that life is always peaceful with respect for others</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>ya memang saya pakai translate</p><p>dengan niat bantu...</p><p>maaf ya kalau salah</p><p>jangan lupa follow ya</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "a-jawablah-pertanyaan-pertanyaan-berikut-dengan-benar-the-toxt-is-352",
            "question": "A Jawablah pertanyaan-pertanyaan berikut dengan benar    The toxt is for no 12\r\nSita Look at the giraffes. They have curly eyelashes\r\nDini Yes, they do Tholr eyelashes are adorable\r\nSita And look at the zobras. They have black and\r\nwhite stripes on thelr bodies. Andri Guys, do you know\r\nthat each zebra has different pattern?\r\nSita They do? That's very interesting\r\n1. What do they say about the animals?\r\nA. Sila says that giraffes have curly eyelashes\r\nB. Andri says that each zebra has the same patter\r\nC. Sita says that giraffes have black and white stripes\r\nD. Dini says that zebras have curly eyelashes\r\n2 \"Their eyelashes are adorable\" What is the synonym of\r\nthe underlined word?\r\nA. Ugly\r\nC. Awlul\r\nB. Beautiful\r\nD. Bad\r\nThe text is for no 3-6\r\nTHIS IS MY HOUSE\r\na\r\nh\r\nV\r\nIc\r\n7\r\nHello I My name is a Andri and this is my house. My\r\nhouse is a quite big. It has got two floors; a ground floor\r\nand a first floor. It has also got an attic and a basement On\r\nthe ground floor there is the hall, the kitchen, a pantry, the\r\nliving room, a blg dining room and a tollet. On the first floor\r\nthere are three bedrooms, one bathroom and a big\r\ncomidor. My bedroom is between my parents' bedroom and\r\nthe bathroom. My sister's bedroom is in front of mine.\r\nI love my bedroom, but I also like the attic. In the attic\r\n1 keep some of my books and my old toys. I like to spend\r\nmy time there because it is very\r\nspacious and there is a big sofa there where I sometimes take\r\na nap comportable and cozy\r\n9.\r\n3. How many floors are there?\r\nA. There are two floors\r\nB. There is one floor\r\nC. There are two ground floor\r\nD. There are three floors\r\n10.\r\nC\r\n11.\r\n4. Where is the living room?\r\nh. On the first floor\r\nB. On the basement\r\nC. On the ground floor\r\nD. On the second floor\r\nWhy does he like to be in the attic?\r\nA. Because it is very spacious and there is a big sofa thoro\r\nwhere he sometimos take a nap,\r\nB. Because there are two swings and he somoumos play\r\nthere\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>3. a. there are two floor</p><p>4. a. on ghe first floor</p><p>5. a. because it is very spacious and there is a big sofa there where i sometimes tak a nap comportable and cozy</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "explaining-yaur-self-when-in-the-past-tense-141",
            "question": "Explaining yaur self when in the past tense",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>i was a very bad person</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>kalo salah sori cuk</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "how-the-rainbow-is-produced-782",
            "question": "How the rainbow is produced?\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><h3>Sunlight looks white. When sunlight hits and is reflected by water droplets, the light will be dispersed and widened so that the colors in the rainbow appear.</h3>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "this-text-is-for-question-numbers-14-17-my-neighbour-mr-and-mrs-937",
            "question": "This text is for question numbers 14-17    My Neighbour\r\nMr. And Mrs. Ruslan are my neighbors. They have two children,\r\na son and a daughter. Their names are Fahril and Mayada. Mr. Ruslan is a lecturer in\r\na state university in our town. Mrs. Ruslanis a house wife. She likes cooking many kinds\r\nof food. She often invites me to cook together in her kitchen. Mr. Ruslan's family has some\r\npets. There are some birds, a cat and two rabits. I sometimes feed them. I like guing there\r\nbecause they are kind and friendly. They always show good attitude to everyone.\r\n14. Does Ruslan's family live far from the writer's house?\r\na. Yes, they do\r\nc. Yes, it does\r\nb. No, they do not\r\nd. No, it doesn't\r\n15. Where does Mr. Ruslan work? He works in a.....\r\na. University\r\nc. kitchen\r\nb. school\r\nd. company\r\n16. I sometimes feed them. The underlined word means.......\r\na. ask food to somebody or something\r\nb.give food to somebody or something\r\nC. eat food with somebody\r\nd. take food froom somebody\r\n17. \" she ofteninvites me to cook together in her kitchen.\"The word \"me\" refers to.....\r\na, the teacher\r\nc. Mayada\r\nc. the writer\r\nd. Mr. Ruslan\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>14. b</p><p>15. a</p><p>16. b</p><p>17. c</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>i&#039;m not sure about number 14, i&#039;m sorry </p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "cerita-maling-kundang-dalam-bahasa-inggris-861",
            "question": "Cerita maling kundang dalam bahasa Inggris\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p>Jawaban:</p><p></p><p>Long time ago, in a small village near the beach in West Sumatera, lived a woman and her son, Malin Kundang. Malin Kundang&#039;s father had passed away when he was a baby, and he had to live hard with his mother.</p><p></p><p>Malin Kundang was a healthy, dilligent, and strong child. He usually went to the sea to catch fish, and brought it to his mother, or sold it in the town.</p><p></p><p>One day, when Malin Kundang was sailing as usual, he saw a merchant&#039;s ship which was being raided by a small band of pirates. With his brave and power, Malin Kundang defeated the pirates. The merchant was so happy and asked Malin Kundang to sail with him. Malin Kundang agreed.</p><p></p><p>Many years later, Malin Kundang became a wealthty merchant, with a huge ship, loads of trading goods, many ship crews, and a beautiful wife. In his journey, his ship landed on a beach. The villagers reconigzed him, and the news ran fast in the town: Malin Kundang became a rich man and now he is here. His mother, in deepful sadnees after years of loneliness, ran to the beach to meet her beloved son again.</p><p></p><p>When the mother came, Malin Kundang, in front of his well dressed wife, his crews and his own gloriness, denied to meet that old, poor and dirty woman. For three times she begged Malin Kundang and for three times yelled at him. At last Malin Kundang said to her \"Enough, old woman! I have never had a mother like you, a dirty and ugly peasant!\" Then he ordered his crews to set sail.</p><p></p><p>Enraged, she cursed Malin Kundang that he would turn into a stone if he didn&#039;t apologize. Malin Kundang just laughed and set sail.</p><p></p><p>In the quiet sea, suddenly a thunderstorm came. His huge ship was wrecked and it was too late for Malin Kundang to apologized. He was thrown by the wave out of his ship, fell on a small island, and suddenly turned into stone.</p><p></p><p>Penjelasan: </p><p>hope yoy find this helpful^\u2022^</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "4-amara-was-sick-three-days-ago-362",
            "question": "4. (+) Amara was sick three days ago\r\n(-)\r\n(?)\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>(-)Amara was not sick three days ago</p><p>(?)was Amara sick three days ago</p><p></p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>&gt;//&lt;</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                },
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>(+) Amara was sick three days ago\n</p><p>(-) Amara \u00a0wasn&#039;t sick three days ago\n</p><p>(?)\u200b Was Amara sick three days ago? yes, she was. no, she wasn&#039;t</p><p></p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "slug": "look-at-the-body-of-the-latter-can-you-find-the-following-items-957",
            "question": "Look at the body of the latter. can you find the following items    a. the date\r\nb. the time\r\nc. the contact for RSV\r\nd. the dress code\u200b",
            "attachments": [],
            "answers": [
                {
                    "answer": "<p><strong>Jawaban:</strong></p><p>D.Thw dress code</p><p><strong>Penjelasan:</strong></p><p>Maaf kalo salah</p>",
                    "attachments": []
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}